## **Abhishek Rawat**

# Senior Software Engineer

# Summary

Experienced Systems and Networks professional with 9+ years of experience

Experience in Networks and wireless communication

Experience in Algorithm Design and Development for WLAN driver features

Experience in Real Time Systems and Embedded development

Experience in Development and Support for large scale deployment(multi-million) of Driver solution (All global Tier-I Handset Manufacturers)

Key contributor in Feature/Product Commercialization

Specialties: Network Systems Design and Development

Wireless Technologies: 802.11(n), 802.15, 802.15.4, GSM, GPRS

# Experience

## Senior Software Engineer at Apple

August 2015 - Present

#### Staff Software Engineer at Ruckus Wireless

May 2014 - July 2015 (1 year 3 months)

11ac wave-2 [MU-MIMO enabled] Access-Point [AP] development

Firmware lead role for First Enterprise Class wave-2 AP [R710]

#### Senior Software Engineer at Ruckus Wireless

April 2013 - May 2014 (1 year 2 months)

11ac Access Point development.

Firmware lead for 11ac wave-1 Access Point product.

#### **Senior Engineer at Qualcomm**

December 2009 - April 2013 (3 years 5 months)

Designed, developed and commercialization key WLAN driver features successfully over various generations of WLAN mobile chipset-solutions - both Discrete(SDIO based) and Integrated.

#### Details:

-802.11n WLAN Single-Channel Concurrency(single device, Dual session) and Bluetooth Coexistence feature design and development

-802.11n WLAN Multi-Channel Concurrency(single device, Dual session) and Bluetooth Coexistence feature design and development

802.11n WLAN and Bluetooth Coexistence Feature design and development:

- WLAN Station and Bluetooth (4.0) Coexistence
- WLAN Soft-AP(Tethering) and Bluetooth (4.0) Coexistence
- WLAN Wi-Fi Direct (Peer-to-Peer) and Bluetooth (4.0) Coexistence
- WLAN with Bluetooth-AMP coexistence Design and Development

Evaluation Kit development for WinCE based driver for RF characterization

- -Development communication interface
- -Enhanced User-Interface for GUI-tool

Frames Parser Optimization:

-Achieved 50% memory foot-print reduction

#### **Graduate Student at University of Minnesota**

September 2007 - November 2009 (2 years 3 months)

Masters in Computer Science.

Masters Project: On Demand Time Synchronization for Wireless Sensor Networks with Prof. Tian He.

#### **Engineering Intern at Qualcomm**

February 2009 - September 2009 (8 months)

Windows Mobile based Wi-Fi driver development

#### Graduate Student (Research Assistant) at University of Minnesota

April 2008 - December 2008 (9 months)

ePCRN development at Family Medicine and Health Care Dept., University of Minnesota-Twin Cities.

#### **Intern at Qualcomm**

June 2008 - September 2008 (4 months)

Windows Mobile based Wi-Fi Driver Evaluation Kit development.

Wi-Fi 802.11 Frames Parser Optimization

#### Software Engineer at Aricent, India

June 2005 - July 2007 (2 years 2 months)

Worked as a software developer in Nokia- Base Transceiver Software Development project:

- Developed GSM Layer 3 module in Channel Management.
- Developed modules for communication and UI in generic R&D tester.
- Designed and Co-Developed Modules Features for Coverage Enhancement.
- System level testing support.

## Education

## **University of Minnesota-Twin Cities**

Master of Science (M.S.), Computer Science, 2007 - 2009

### **Motilal Nehru National Institute Of Technology**

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science, 2001 - 2005

Activities and Societies: - Student Activity Center, Coordinator. - Annual National Technical Meet [Avishkar-2004], Coordinator. - Annual Cultural Meet [Culrav-2005] Coordinator. - Chief Student Editor - Annual Institute Magazine - Srijan-2005, English Editorial Board Member [Srijan 2003, 04].

#### St. Paul's Senior Secondary School

High School, 1998 - 2000

Activities and Societies: Debate Team, Quiz Team, Extempore Team, House Captain, Creative Writing Team G.D.Birla Memorial School, Ranikhet, India

AISSCE 1998, Junior High/Intermediate/Middle School Education and Teaching, 1994 - 1998

**Activities and Societies:** - Debate, Extempore Team. - Creative Writing [English and Hindi]. - Junior Athletics [House Team]. - School Gymnastics Team. - School Cross-Country Team.

# **Abhishek Rawat**

Senior Software Engineer



Contact Abhishek on LinkedIn